welcome to another installment of the
right chest and redux video series if
you haven't been following along it will
probably be much easier to start at the
beginning since each video builds on
where the previous video of staff and
remember to get up to speed on Redux
itself you really can't beat ya diode
videos
paradoxes creator Dan aber muss so far
everything we've done has been
synchronous and that was great for
getting familiar with how to get the
redox or wired up their view but in real
application we're gonna need to make
asynchronous calls to deal with API is
on our server that's what the rest of
the series is going to focus on will be
picking up where the last video left off
but we'll be expanding our example
beyond a single form input and output so
let's remove the previous tags from our
index HTML and clean up some of the code
around those tags so that we can focus
on a new functionality so to start off
I'm gonna go ahead and close the title
form tag and protect files will be
looking at those anymore I'm gonna go
into index HTML we're going to pick
played a horn the H are in our sample
output remove those and then indexed ijs
we're not gonna need these to require
statements anymore so I'll take those
out and then in our reducer we can
remove the case for change title we can
go into actions that Jas and we can
remove the exports for change title and
the change table action creator now the
cleanup stun we're gonna need to install
couple more MPN modules the first we're
gonna install is the Redux dunk
middleware and what this is going to do
is give us the ability to create action
creators that instead of just returning
a static object they can reach her at a
function and that function is going to
be the key to allowing us to let us
continue to run in a synchronous manner
while we do asynchronous work within the
function that those action creators are
going to return and we'll see how this
all works once we get everything
installed and setup
so it's going to our terminal and I
still have the Westpac that server
running so I'm just gonna clear that out
and we're gonna NPM install with the
same flag redux dash dunk and so we can
focus on the front end riot and redux
code and we don't have to worry about
setting up our backend server with
express how happy I ask something like
that we're gonna install another and
p.m. package called JSON server we're
gonna install that globally JSON servers
gonna do is give us a service within
point that we can hit based on a static
JSON file was so we can create that file
save in our project set up our test data
and the great thing about this is we
don't do any real set up other than
creating the file but we can hit with
get ready class and get that about we
can also post put delete pretty much
anything you do with a regular service
and it's just going to update the file
so great little utility when you're
working on something Friday and you need
to fix your back and services so that's
done installing a good clear that out
and we're going to create a file on TV
that chase on
and now that we have this file we're
gonna go ahead and add some JSON to act
as our back-end data so going to create
the old reliable task application so
that again rather than focusing on the
details of the application we can keep
our focus on the right and redux parts
to make sure the DVD JSON is saved
we're gonna go back into a terminal and
we're gonna go ahead and start up the
server for that so I'm gonna do that by
typing in JSON dash server and the name
of our final and when we run this will
see that this is running at localhost
port 3000 and it's showing us that we
have a resource called tasks in this
path so I take this path and I open
another terminal window I should be able
to curl the GET request to that has
resource and point and it will return
that has arrived so in our API is gonna
respond when we get requests and that's
all we need for now so it's gonna clear
that out and we killed the web dev
server so I'm gonna run out again with
my M him run death command a valid
bundle so we can go ahead and get
started with the new code in the index
JSP file we want to add require
statement to pull in that redux thunk
module and because we've introduced this
redox middle where we're going to have
to make some updates to our create store
functionality that we have down here so
I comment out the old one so we have it
as a reference for now I'm gonna create
a new variable create store with
middleware and this is gonna be set to
equal redux not compose which is going
to take our middleware and it's going to
result in a function and in compose
function we want to call redux is
applying middleware method will pass it
in some redux compose returns a function
and that function takes redux is create
store function and that combination
intern returns yet
another function and that's what creates
tour with middleware is gonna going to
be so it's going to be the resulting
function from this entire operation so
that we can call that with a reducer and
will get a Redux store in our previous
examples we looked at the Redux stores
three methods we have get state dispatch
and subscribe and when you subscribe to
get our tags to update any time there
was a state change well in this new
application we're going to use multiple
tags and those are all gonna need to
respond to state updates so rather than
having to put this code in every single
tag we're going to build this new
application with the concept of a parent
container jack and the parent container
tag is going to contain all of the other
tags and makeup application and its
gonna be responsible for responding to
state updates and making sure that all
of its child tags get updated so it's
great that tag now
so I'm gonna create a tag on the tax
folder and I'm going to call it to do
dash at that tank and I'm getting given
its route tags and it's also going to
need to set a script acts younger than
in some actions in my to do at tag so
I'm gonna have to require statement that
pulls in the actions that Jas file I'm
also going to create a variable for the
store which is going to be passed into
this tags for the options and then I'm
gonna add my call to stored at subscribe
so that I can respond to state updates
anytime state changes I want to take
that new state and assign it to a
variable within my tag sewn inside this
dot state
storied I get state and he stayed up
there is going to require the attack
updates so I recalled in this . update
any order for both of those this
references to work properly in a bind
that function to this so at this point
any time the state update subscribers
get triggered a call stored at get state
to get the newest version of the state
of sign it into this local state
variable and update the tag and that
update is going to cause this tag and
any tags that are referenced inside of
it to update so that's gonna push those
state updates of the way through our
entire application and the first thing
are tagged needs is a tech to render out
our tests that are coming from that date
will be set up and we're going to want
to display that inside the 20 tag so I'm
gonna add this task list tag into the
body here in our task list tag is gonna
take the tasks that it needs to display
their natural you again this attribute
is going to be available within task
list on the OPs object we're going to
pass it an expression and in that
expression we want to make a call to
this dot state which we are signing the
entire state down and subscribe and
we're gonna call tests property on that
state so we get that updated stage now
to get assigned to state down here
and that state is ultimately going to
have a property on a contest that will
contain the list that we got our API
call now that we have the task list tag
set up what's going to create that so in
the tag directory create a new file
called task list that tag and just like
any other tank will go ahead and the
route tags first and inside there we
want to set up UL which in turn is going
to contain an ally and we give that a
lie in each statement and if you
remember from previous videos as hell
right handles loops we're gonna say for
each task in the tasks that were passed
in the options we want to create a new
ally element and for now let's just give
that some taxed so we'll take the name
of the task will drop that inside the Li
so at this point we have a container tag
that set up to handle changes in our
state and we have our task list tag
that's going to display our tasks we
have our fake API set up so now we need
the action creator set up so that we can
make that a sink all to get those tasks
from this so we're gonna go into actions
that Jas and we're gonna create a
function called load tasks and that
function is gonna reach her in a
function okay this is where their redux
thank nowhere comes into play and this
function that were returning is gonna
get past and the dispatch and get state
methods from our store inside that
function we can make our XHR request so
requests are open we want to make a GET
request to that localhost 3000 / tasks
that we looked at earlier and then we're
going to handle the result of that
through the request I onload function
and we want to send the request so in
the onload I'm going to end in his
statement and this way we only respond
to valid or successful status codes
gonna take that request text and we want
to parse the JSON and assigned to a
variable called data and now we want to
make 'cause dispatch
which we got past him by redux and we
went to call tasks loaded with our data
value tasks loaded is an action creator
that we still need to create that's
going to create that now so we'll create
the empty function tasks loaded and
that's gonna take Artest's array and we
want to return an action object when
this one will give it a type tests
loaded ammo Pasadena data property with
a value test and we're gonna need to be
able to call load tasks from outside of
our actions that Jas file so we're going
to expose that in the module that
expert's statement at the top of our
final and now let's go update or reduce
her to handle this
the first thing I want to do is update
my default state where I have the old
titled assault title update that to be
tasked with an empty array so are
starting state is going to be an empty
set of tasks now he can add the case for
action creator that returned has
exploded and then of course we need to
handle that so we're gonna just like we
did before returning to object that a
sign the take our existing state and any
new properties for that state merge them
into a new object and reach her in that
from a reducer and now to make sure all
of this will work we need to do some
plumbing so we want to add require
statements for our tags right here in
text i jus and our call to riot
we're gonna update that catch all and
we're just going to mount the to-do app
directly and then on our index HTML file
you need to add our to-do app tag and
now we're going to go into our to do at
tag when I had a call to the tags mount
event and I get that an anonymous
function and in this function of wanna
make a call a stored at this patch and I
wanna call my asynchronous action
creator load tasks so this is gonna kick
off the whole process so in this tag
mounts actions . low tasks will be
called
it'll return a function internally that
function is kinda maker XHR request and
when that is done it's going to dispatch
or other action that's going to go into
the reducer gonna replace rnt Alyssa
tasks with the ones from the API and we
should see the task order on the page so
let's go to our browser and check that
out and everything's wired up properly
we should see these two values displayed
so we're loading this data from the JSON
server node module it's running locally
so it's super fast but if there was some
kind of delay due to network bottleneck
for the service being slow for some
reason we went to indicate that the data
is loading and I have a just sit there
with an empty task list and then
suddenly have the test here so let's go
ahead and set up an artificial delay
using a set time out so that we can test
out and incorporated loading indicator
so you're going to actions that Jas
we're making our XHR request and I'm
going to wrap the request on sand and a
set time out with a delay of two seconds
to now go back to the browser and
refresh the page will set their plank
about two seconds and our tasks appear
so now we have a sufficient delay to
test against to set up our indicator
light said the first thing I want to do
is my text directory I'm gonna add a
file from a leading indicator of loading
indicator dye tank and will give loading
indicator through tags loading dash
indicator and I just want a simple
animated gifs I'm gonna go ahead and
grab that for my filesystem an additive
project so we'll see here I have loading
that Jeff it's just a little spinner and
in my loading indicator tank can add an
image source and i cant have it point to
loading down shift the next thing we
need to do is this idea for a show this
so we're gonna have a show attribute
this is one of riots built-in attributes
and will pass at an expression and that
expression is going to be dependent on a
loading flag that will pass in as
natural beauty of the leading indicator
Tang so access that through this tops
and now we have our tag set up and go
back into indexed ijs when you want to
add a required for this will go into our
container tank to do add that tag
loading indicator and again leading
indicator is going to rely on a loading
flag passed in as an attribute
surpassing loading with an expression
and we're gonna reference this starts
state DOT is loading and at this point
this property doesn't exist on our
state's 01 we need to go created to by
default this will just results who
falsely value so we're loading indicator
of this remain hit but we do want to be
able to show it and so let's go into our
actions file and inactions that Jas
we're going to add a new function called
titles loading and toggle voting is
gonna take it is loading and unloading
is going to return an object with a type
toggle loading and a data value is
loading so now we need to go into a
reducer and handle this action to back
and indexed ijs will add a case for
toggle loading and in that case we're
going to use our object that a sign
again we're going to take the existing
state with an updated is loading
property and we're going to use the
action that data value for that then
returned that new state and now I'm
gonna go bad actions that Jas an
interlude tasks function we're gonna
make a call to dispatch with the toggle
loading passing at a value of true the
very beginning of our function that does
our exit XHR call and at this point if
we go back to our browser and we refresh
we should see our loading indicator and
then armed away and our task slowed but
are leading indicator just sits there so
it's going back into our code and fix
that
so in dhahran load handler we're going
to make another call the dispatch with
toggle loading and we're gonna pass it
false and now we go back to our browser
refresh should the indicator delay and
we get our tasks and hides we're loading
indicator thank you for watching hope
you found this video helpful and be sure
to keep an eye out for the next video in
the serious